Mary Florence O'Shea Papers
Dominican University Archives and Special Collections
- Series 6: Outer Drive East Condominium
  - Senior Citizen Sewer Charge Refund, 1994 - 2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Loans - First Bank Mortgage, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Gold Coast Bath Systems, Inc., 1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Loans - Calumet Securities Corporation, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The 400 Condominium Association - Parking License Agreement, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Loans - BSI Finanical Services, Inc., 2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Sub-series 1: Slides
    - Outer Drive East (33 slides total), 1970 - 1973
    - Outer Drive East - MAC (17 slides total), 1971
    - Outer Drive East - Lake Shore Drive Realignment (25 slides total), 1983
  - Sub-series 2: Photographs
    - Lake Shore Drive Realignment, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Condominium interior, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Views from balcony, 1985 - 1986, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Views of Outer Drive East, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Series 7: Travel / Continuing Studies
  Gamelan Musical Troupe
  Sitting gamelan ensemble is carved from Diospyros Celebica, a type of tree that is found in Indonesia.
  One (1) wooden seated male figurine with a gong, carved as single piece of wood. The gong hangs from an architectural frame, which is carved with decorations on the side that faces away from the figure.
  Two (2) wooden kneeling male figurines wearing robes, pointed hats, and earrings. Each figurine holds up his right hand and has his left on his left knee. His hair falls onto his back and he has a band across his chest. One figurine is two-toned wood and the other is a single tone.
  Two (2) wooden seated male figurines, each with his hands on a rectangular instrument. Each figure has his arms bent at the elbows and wears a hat with one raised, pointed edge. He also wears a robe tied around his torso. Both figurines are carved from two-toned wood. The instrument has a triangular pattern carved onto it in low relief.
  One (1) wooden seated male figuring carved from wood of a single tone. He rests his hands on a rectangular instrument with a square pattern carved onto its front panel. He wears a robe tied around his torso and a hat with one raised, pointed edge.
  Two (2) wooden sated male figurines, each holding a cylindrical instrument under his left arm. Each rests on his knees, wears a robe tied around his torso, and has a hat with one raised, pointed edge. Both figurines are carved from two-toned wood.
  Two (2) wooden seated male figurines, each with a large drum across his knees. Each wears a robe tied around his torso, and has a hat with one raised, pointed edge. The drums have different decorative carvings on them that distinguish the two figures. One drum has three registers with a triangular pattern running around the head of the drum. The other drum is not divided into registers; it has a triangular pattern around its head and vertical bands that run from top to bottom.
  Four (4) carved wooden mallets: One (1) dark brown with cylindrical head, 3.1cm long; one (1) light brown with wedge-shaped head, 2.8cm long; one (1) dark brown with wedge-shaped head, 3.9cm long; and one (1) with a large cylindrical head, 4.3cm long and 1cm diameter.
  The average dimensions of the Gamelan figurines are 12.5cm x 5.2cm x 2.6cm. Pair of Figurines
  Wooden Figures
  Two (2) wooden figurines, one male and one female, measuring 14cm x 4cm x 6.6 cm. The male figure holds an umbrella in his right hand while his left hand hangs at his side. He wears sandal, a robe, an overcoat, and a head wrap. The female stands with her arms at her sides, her left hand slightly behind her. She wears sandals, a robe, a knee-length overcoat, and a strand of beads around her neck. She wears a woven hat and her hair extends from one side of the hat and over her shoulder. The wood is light in color and each figurine stands on an oval base.
  - Passports, 1953 - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Britain - Paris - Lebanon, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Istanbul, Turkey, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Travel Guide, Singapore Travel Service, ca. 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Toshogu Shrine, Japan, ca. 1954 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Toshogu Shrine, Japan, ca. 1954 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The Main Passage, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - International Certificates of Vaccination, 1971 - 1974 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Munich, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - The Chicago Council on Foreign Relations - Alaska, June 30 - July 14, 1979, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Chicago Council on Foreign Relations - Scandinavia, July 24 - August 9, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Island World of Britain, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Summer River Views and Seascopes aboard the yacht Argonaut, August 9-22, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Mallorca / Spain / Portugal, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - The Field Museum - Te Maori exhibition, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - New Zealand Cultural Expedition, April 14 - May 4, 1986, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - China Trip, September 2-23 (see also: FFC3, D3), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Cambridge / UCLA Program, July 5 - August 15, 1987, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - The Cambridge / UCLA Program - Notebooks, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Canals and Old Masters: Treasures of the Netherlands and Belgium, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago - Chicago Architecture 1972-1922 series, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - UCLA Extension - Discovering London Through its Architecture, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Trinity / Simthsonian Seminar, August 11-26, 1989, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Paris Program, July 8-28, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Maori Support Group, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Elderhostel Program, France, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Splendors of Italy Tour, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Britain / Scotland, folder 1 of 2, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Britain / Scotland, folder 2 of 2, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Elderhostel Fine Arts Programmes 1994, From Antiquity to the Renaissance, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - California, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Harold Washington College - Introduction to MS Word 6, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 2: Ephemera
    - Gamelan Ensemble (15 pieces), ca. 1953
    - Wooden figures (1 male and 1 female), ca. 1953
  - Sub-series 3: Postcard Collection
    - Burmese postcards, ca. 1953; 20 cards (Box 13)
    - Thai postcards, ca. 1953; 2 cards (Box 13)
    - Indonesian postcards, ca. 1954; 2 cards (Box 13)
    - Philippines postcards, ca. 1954; 1 cards (Box 13)
    - Mexican postcards, ca. 1950s; 10 cards (Box 13)
    - Irish postcards, ca. 1974; 12 cards (Box 13)
    - Hawaiian postcards, ca. 1975; 18 cards (Box 13)
    - German postcards, ca. 1978; 9 cards (Box 13)
    - Russian postcards, ca. 1978; 27 cards (Box 13)
    - Alaskan postcards, ca. 1979; 3 cards (Box 13)
    - Scottish postcards ( Island World of Britain ), ca. 1983; 10 cards (Box 13)
    - On board the Argonaut ( Summer River Views and Seascapes ), ca. 1984; 1 cards (Box B 11, F 3)
    - Spainish and Portuguese postcards, ca. 1985; 165 loose; 5 sets, 231 cards total (Box 13)
    - New Zealand postcards, ca. 1986; 125 cards, plus 5 tiny postcard booklets (Box 13)
    - Chinese postcards, ca. 1986; 30 loose; 5 empty covers; 17 sets, 208 cards total (Box B 11, F4; B13)
    - The Netherlands and Belgium, ca. 1986; 112 cards (Box B 11, F5; B13)
    - English postcards, ca. 1988; 29 cards (Box 14)
    - French postcards, ca. 1992; 140 cards (Box 14)
    - Italian postcards, ca. 1993; 161 cards (Box 14)
    - British and Scottish postcards, ca. 1994; 99 cards (Box 14)
    - California postcards, ca. 1995; 23 cards (Box 14)
  - Sub-series 4: Slides
    - Hong Kong etc. (6 slides total), 1954
    - Mexico (5 boxes, 145 slides total), 1950s
    - Hawaii (31 slides total), 1968
    - Nassau (34 slides total), 1968
    - Main Passage(14 slides total), 1971
    - Golden Odyssey (7 boxes, 138 slides total), 1971
    - Golden Odyssey slide carousel 1 of 2 (140 slides total), 1971
    - Golden Odyssey slide carousel 2 of 2 (146 slides total), 1971
    - European Capitals (2 boxes, 67 slides total), 1974
    - European Capitals, Ireland slide carousel 1 of 3 (123 slides total), 1974
    - European Capitals, Lucerne / Venice / Florence slide carousel 2 of 3 (120 slides total), 1974
    - European Capitals, Florence / Rome / Wantiez slide carousel 3 of 3 (121 slides total), 1974
    - Christmas 75 Cruise slide carousel (139 slides total), 1975
    - Russia, 1978
    - Russia slide carousel (140 slides total), 1978 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Munich slide carousel 1 of 2 (139 slides total), 1978
    - Munich slide carousel 2 of 2 (87 slides total), 1978
    - Munich slide carousel 2 of 2 papers, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Alaska (2 boxes, 54 slides total), 1979
    - Alaska slide carousel (122 slides total), 1979
    - Isles of Britain slide carousel (135 slides total), 1983
    - Spain / Portugal slide carousel (140 slides total), 1985
    - China, Great Wall (18 slides total), 1986
    - China, Palace Museum (20 slides total with 4 missing), 1986
    - China slide carousel 1 of 3 (123 slides total), 1986
    - China slide carousel 2 of 3 (140 slides total), 1986
    - China slide carousel 3 of 3 (140 slides total), 1986
    - New Zealand needs to be organized slide carousel(140 slides total), 1986
    - New Zealand pull outs (114 slides total), 1986
    - Art Institute Tripe slide carousel 3 of 3 (153 slides total), 1988
  - Sub-series 5: Photographs
    - Paris, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Thailand (Bangkok), 1953 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Road Trip, ca. 1950s (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Ireland, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Germany, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Summer River Views and Seascapes, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Madrid, ca. 1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - New Zealand, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - California, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Series 8: Personal Papers, general
  - Sub-series 1: Correspondence
    - Bhandari, Puru, 1990 - 1991 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Bird, Maureen (nee Stokes) and Neville, 2007 - 2009, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Cox, Esther and Lauren A., 1984 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Fox, Etha B. (Bea), 1977 - 1998, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Cox, Esther and Lauren A., 1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Mother and Father, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - O'Neill, Sister Thomas Aquinas, 1942 - 1946 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - O'Shea, Uncle Ben and Aunt Nell, 1942 - 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - O'Shea, Mary Florence to Mary Jane O'Shea, 1953 - 1963, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Tolchinsky, Nelly, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Vincent, John, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, A, 1993 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, B, 1986 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, C, 2008 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, D, 2008 - 2009, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, F, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, G, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, H, 2008 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, J, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, K, 1985 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, L, 2008 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, M, 2008 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, N, 2008 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, P, 1988 - 2009 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, R, 2008 - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, S, 2007 - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, T, 2008 - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, W, 1985 - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Z, 2008 - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Christmas Cards, blank, ca. 2000s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, unknown, 1981, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series 2: Prayer Cards
    - In Memoriam, A - M, 1950 - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - In Memoriam, N - W, 1961 - 2007 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - In Remembrance of Ordinations, 1951 - 2006 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Sub-series 3: Chronological Files
    - Holy Cross - Easter Offering, 1928, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Holy Cross School Solemn Closing Exercises, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Archdiocese of Chicago, Board of Education - Holy Cross School Diploma, 1933 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - The High Schoool of St. Thomas the Apostle - The 1934 Memory Book, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - The High Schoool of St. Thomas the Apostle - The Apostalite, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - The High Schoool of St. Thomas the Apostle - Crede Mihi, Vol. IV, No. 6, 1937 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Defense Stamp Album, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - War Ration Books, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - New York Life Insurance Company, 1946 - 1947 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "The Effect of Boron Deficiency on Plant Metabolism and Growth", Masters of Science essay submission, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - The University of Chicago - Masters of Science, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Soil from the Tomb of Blessed Martin De Porres, OP, ca. 1947 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Writings on Catholicism, ca. 1940s (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - 1040 U.S. Individual Income Tax Form, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Papal Blessings, 1955 - 2000 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - The North American Company Insurance Policy, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Old Saint Mary's Church, ca. 1965 - 2002 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Clippings - Pope John Paul I Begins His Reign, 1978 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Pope John Paul II in Chicago (see also: Oversized), 1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Estate of Mary Jane O'Shea, 1982 - 1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Family Record of Mary Florence O'Shea, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sr. Candida Lund Memorial Materials, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Rev. Edward Stokes Obituaries, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Driver's License, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Mahogany Mink Coat, 2005 - 2006 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Safe Deposit - Content List, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Memorial Books, Blake-Lamb Funeral Home, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Address List, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Holy Cross - Directory of the Class of '33, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Sub-series 4: Ephemera
    - Mahogany Mink Coat, ca. 1980s
    - Mahogany Mink Hat, n.d.
    - Madonna collection, 7 items total, n.d.
  - Sub-series 5: Slides
    - Chicago - Boats (4 slides total), 1965 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wantiez, Belgian Relations (19 slides total), 1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Altar Soc + Violent (23 slides total), 1969
    - Astronauts (11 slides total), 1969
    - Chicago - Parade (8 slides total), 1970 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Chicago and Condo (6 slides total), 1971 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Stokes Family (7 slides total), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Chicago - Bicentennial Parade (8 slides total), 1976 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Chicago and Condo (20 slides total), 1972 - 1979 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Family (19 slides total), 1994
  - Sub-series 6: Photographs
    - Mary Florence O'Shea, portraits and candid, ca. 1923 - 1997, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - St. Thomas the Apostle High School - Class of June 1937, 1937 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Audience with Pope Pius XII, ca. 1955 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Mary Florence and Mary Jane O'Shea, 1956 - 1975, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Friends and Family, 1954 - 1970 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Friends and Family, 1973 - 1989 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Friends and Family, 1990 - 2007 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - St. Thomas the Apostle 60th Anniversary Reunion, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Friends and Family, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Negatives, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)